

ABOUT ME

I graduated International Trade – Customs Management major and I have over 1.5 years of experience in logistics and import-export sector. With the meticulous, enthusiasm and willingness to learn, I believe I will go further in this field and bring value to company.

CONTACT









EDUCATION

2019 - 2023

UNIVERSITY OF ECONOMICS HO CHI MINH CITY (UEH)

- Bachelor of International Trade –
 Customs Management
- GPA: 8.58/10.00 (Distinction)

AWARDS

- Achieved Student With 5
 Merits of UEH University 2021
- Achieved UEH 500 Excellent Assignment Awards 2021
- Achieved Prize C of the "Young Economist" award for the research 2022
- Presented a scientific research topic by a representative at the seminar "Challenges in the field of Customs - Foreign Trade in the post-Covid period" 2022

BUITHITUONG VY

EXPORT DOCUMENT STAFF

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Short and mid-term objective: Obtain a suitable position in logistics field that I can contribute my knowledge, experience and skills to the development of the company.

Long-term objective: Become an Document executive in the coming 3-5 years.

WORK EXPERIENCE

VINAPHARMA PHARMACEUTICAL TECHNOLOGY JOINT STOCK COMPANY

08/2024 - 09/2024

Import - Export assistant

- Prepared and issued purchase orders, communicated with foreign suppliers to place orders.
- Worked with FWD to track shipment progress and resolved any issues that may arise. Kept track of shipment timelines and provided updates to relevant departments.
- Compared received goods with purchase orders and coordinate with the warehouse team to ensure accurate inventory.
- Translated product specifications and other related documents as needed.

VIET NAM ASC TRANS JOINT STOCK COMPANY 12/2022 Sales Executive

12/2022 - 07/2024

- Searched and gave advice to customers related to the company's Logistics services such as: Air freight rate, Sea freight (LCL/FLC), Customs clearance, licenses...
- Prepared Freight quotation and sent to Customers.
- Cooperated with Docs/Ops/Cus/Coordinator dept to handle shiptments.
- Took care current jobs and handle if trouble arise.

Gained:

- Had over 1.5 year-experience in handling importing Medical devices,
 Cosmetics, Health Supplements, Foods,...
- Registered import license for Medical devices.
- Fully understanding of Export-Import process.

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- STUDENT UNION OF THE FACULTY OF PUBLIC FINANCE 2020 2021
 Member of the Executive Committee
 - Planned and organized a faculty level "Debate UEH 2021" contest.
 - Planmed and organized activities for students of the Faculty with a scale of about 500 students.
- YOUNG ECONOMIC RESEARCH CLUB YoRE
 Member of Communication and External Relations Department
 - Supported to inform the club's contests and programs to students.
 - Connected media activities with clubs and organizations both inside and outside the university.

SKILLS

- Technical: IC3 (The Internet and Computing Core Certification) includes
 Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Powerpoint); Google Tools.
- Language: English, Chinese
- · Soft skills: presentation, adaptability, problem solving.